Inventory of the Mu'assasat al-dhākirah al-'Irāqīyah [Iraq Memory Foundation] records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Appendix: List of Iraqi Testimonies Interviewees with English subtitles, 2007-2008
  - Hasan Ali Katafa, 2008 May 9; 9.17 minutes
    "From Al-Nasiriah, arrested on 1986 and accused of belonging to Al-Da'wah Party. He was transferred to the General Security Directorate and fiercely tortured with beating, electric shocks and hanging all along the arrest duration for more than one year. He was submitted to the Revolution Court where he was sentenced to life imprisonment and transferred to Abu Ghraib where he had another painful experience with torture for eight years. After his release upon a general pardon he was arrested again in 1997. This testimony was recorded in Al-Nasiriah on 09-05-2008."
  - Mansur Hasan Muhammad, 2008 August 4; 10.02 minutes
    Born in 1932, he's a farmer from Al-Samawa city. His family was pursued for unclear reasons. Many of his brothers and clan members were arrested. Security agents shot his son Hasan dead at their house's door. He filed a lawsuit against the murderer of his son but to no avail. In fact, the rest of his family got arrested, including his daughters. This testimony was recorded in Al-Samawa city on 4-8-2008."
  - Abd Al-Hadi Mu'taq Sultan-Al-Hatem, 2007 September 25; 9.11 minutes
    "From Basra city, a writer. In 1979, his father was arrested for insulting the vice-president. He was tortured despite his old age, at the same time Al-Hadi was arrested for harboring ideas that antagonize Al-Ba'th party doctrines. In 1980, his brothers Qaysar and Amjad got arrested; Amjad was killed mysteriously; as for Qaysar, no trace of him has been found so far. This testimony was recorded in Basra city on 25-9-2007."
  - Sultana Karim Mustafa, 2008 March 16; 8.16 minutes
    In Kurdish with English subtitles. "From Karkuk city, her brother was arrested in 1980, he was 18 years old. He was charged with belonging to Al-Da'wah Party, his arrest coincided with the death of her soldier brother Hashim at the beginning of the war. Abdallah remained in prison for 11 years where he was constantly tortured and that affected both his structure and health leading eventually to his death after his release. This testimony was recorded in Taza city on 16-3-2008."
  - As'ad Mahmud Ahmad, 2008 March 5; 9.44 minutes
    In Kurdish with English subtitles. "Born in 1957 in Al-Sulaymaniah city. In February 1988 planes bombed their village which got later invaded by military forces during Al-Anfal campaigns. His family was deported to the Iranian borders, when they returned, all his family got arrested: his wife, four of his children his mother and brother. No trace was found of them until the regime was toppled; it turned out they had been buried in a mass grave. This testimony was recorded in Al-Sulaymaniah city on 5-3-2008."
  - Ra'd Layim Khilkhal, 2008 May 3; 12.00 minutes
    "Born in Al-Diwaniyah in 1952, he is an officer. Due to the membership of his brother Shaddad in Al-Da'wah Party, all the family members got arrested. After a while, he and his older brother were sent to the military intelligence jail where they were subjected to extreme torture, then imprisoned for three years and discharged. His younger brother Ahmad was executed for joining the Da'wah Party. This testimony was recorded in Al-Diwaniyah city on 3-5-2008."
  - Abd Faysal Al-Sahlani, 2008 January 4; 10.14 minutes
    "Born to a rich family in Al-Nasiriyah city, he was arrested in 1985 for adhering to the communist party. He was placed in solitary confinement for two years. His father was arrested several times. All his family got arrested too and placed for six months in jail number 1. He had two brothers in the military who got arrested for covering for him. He was transferred to the Revolution Court and condemned to death, but on the execution day, the judgment was reduced to life imprisonment. This testimony was recorded in Baghdad city on 4-1-2008."
  - Saleh Muhammed Hussein, 2008 March 7; 9.26 minutes
    In Kurdish with English subtitles. "From Al-Sulaymaniah city; his family had been exterminated in Al-Anfal operations on 17-3-1988. His village was heavily shelled, and then the army led an arrest campaign that targeted the villagers. His wife and 3 children were among the detainees, he kept on asking about their whereabouts but they were being continuously transferred to several prisons in southern and northern districts until they ended up in Nakrat al-Salman Prison. He got no news about them until Saddam's regime was toppled, when the bodies of his children were found with bullet holes in their heads. This testimony was recorded in Al-Sulaymaniah city on 7-3-2008."
  - Mudr Ghani Hamza Abu-Ghunaym, 2008 January 4; 8.53 minutes
    "From Al-Najaf city. In 1978, when the communist party was subject to a fierce attack by Al-Ba'th party, he was arrested as a student along with a group of schoolboys. After this arrest, he reduced his political activities and continued his studies. In 1980, he was arrested and led to the general security headquarters where he was severely tortured resulting in a weakness in his outer limbs of which he suffers till now. In 1991, he was arrested for the third time at the intelligence fifth division headquarters. This testimony was recorded in Baghdad city on 4-1-2008."
  - Qasim Adnan Aziz Rida, 2008 May 8; 8.20 minutes
    "From Al-Nasiriyah city. He was arrested in 1983 and transferred to the fifth division in Baghdad. He was subjected to extreme torturing electrocution, burning and insults. He describes a lot of torturing methods at the prison of the fifth division. He witnessed the atrocious torturing of several women. He was less than 18 years of age; still he was accused of being a member of Al-Da'wah Party and got a 5 year sentence. His brother was executed on the charge of participation in the uprising; he was only 16 years old. This testimony was recorded in Al-Nasiriyah city on 8-5-2008."
  - Muhammad Turki Khudayr Al-Mi'mar, 2008 January 4; 8.57 minutes
    "From Al-Najaf city, he comes from a middle-class family working in construction. He was arrested in 1978 because he insulted Saddam Hussein the then-vice-president. He was taken to Al-Najaf security administration where he was severely tortured. Two weeks after his release, he was arrested again on the same charge. For six months, he was subject to extreme torturing. Then, he got transferred to the Revolution Court, where he got a three year sentence that he spent in Abu Ghraib Prison. This testimony was recorded in Baghdad on 4-1-2008."
  - Muhammad Fulayh Abdul Hasan Al Zalmi, 2008 May 6; 8.18 minutes
    "Born in 1959 in the city of Rumaytha, a school headmaster. His 75 year old father was arrested in 1991 and they found no sign of him. He suffered terribly from the news he received about the security people cruelly torturing his father. He found him after 2003 in a mass grave site. During the time of his father's arrest he was harassed and called the 'Son of the Traitor', then all his funds were confiscated and he was forbidden to travel. Being a school director, he witnesses that there is about 400 orphans at his school due to the execution of their fathers. This testimony was recorded in the city of Rumaytha on 6/5/2008."
  - Darun Nuri Muhammed Hilmi, 2008 March 5; 7.42 minutes
    In Kurdish with English subtitles. "From the city of Halbaja. He was ten years old when his family got massacred during the bombing of his city with chemical weapons on 16/2/1988. He lost his mother, four of his brothers his 82 year old grandma and the family of his uncle and the entire family of his aunt. He remembers the collective bodies of victims that fell down during the chemical bombing. This testimony was recorded in the city of Halbaja on 5/3/2008."
  - Rajiha Na'im Muhammed, 2008 June 15; 8.51 minutes
    "A housewife from the city of Al-Samawa; her husband was arrested many times, charged with disrespecting the authorities. He was tortured gruesomely. In 1982, he was arrested again for the last time; no trace of him was ever found event till the date of the recording of this testimony. Rajiha suffered from the security persecution. When her husband was arrested her house was confiscated and put for sale. This testimony was recorded in the city of Al-Samawa on 15/6/2008."
  - Hadi Marza Zayir Abu-Ghneim, 2008 January 7; 7.27 minutes
    "Born in 1948, in the province of Najaf. He took part in 1977 in the marching towards the grave of Imam Hussein according to the annual Shiite rite, the army forces pursued them and arrested a great number of the participants. They were taken to the military prison of Rashid. He was tortured and insulted for over a year and a half of arrest. He was charged with giving shelter to a member of the Da'wah Party. He was referred to the Revolution Court and was sentenced to 15 years of prison. This testimony was recorded in the Najaf City on 7/1/2008."
  - Karim Abdallah Karim, 2008 March 11; 9.59 minutes
    In Kurdish with English subtitles. "From the city of Sulaymaniyyah, he was arrested in September 1989. He was a soldier. He was accused of sympathizing with Kurdish fighters (Peshmerga). Karim moved to different prisons and camps where he was tortured gruesomely and was sentenced to 9 months of prison with hard labor. When he finished his prison sentence and was released, he was arrested once again and was tortured. A few months later, he was released then he was arrested another time; and thus, throughout his life he kept being arrested repeatedly for no clear reason. This testimony was recorded in the city of Sulaymaniyyah on 11/3/2008."
  - Tarek Safi Abdallah Al-Shahrani, 2007 October 1; 12.15 minutes
    "From the city of Karma Ali in Basra; a soldier specialized in marine engineering. During the uprising of 1991 all his unit's members ran away, the weapons remained unguarded. He took them along with his remaining friend to a safe place. He guarded them until the end of Intifada. Then he was arrested charged with taking part in the Intifada. He was moved between many prisons including the Radwaniyyah Prison. He witnessed the torture of the detainees and their suffering in the prison camps. This testimony was recorded in the city of Karma, on 1/10/2007."
  - Ali Hadi Kraydi, 2007 December 15; 5.48 minutes
    "His brother Muhammad was arrested in 1981 accused of being a member of Al-Da'wah Party. They knew nothing about him until they were informed of his execution and they didn't receive his body. The family of Ali went through a great amount of suffering and pressures by the security officers; they were fought in their work places and were prohibited from working in the state departments. This testimony was recorded in the Kafal District on 15/12/2007."
  - Hamid Abd-Al-Kazim Al-Duray'I, 2007 December 15; 12.15 minutes
    "From Al-Kafal District. In the late 70s, early 80s; three of his brothers were executed charged with being members of religious parties, due to that, the family suffered a lot. The remaining members of the family, including Hamid used to get arrested for any reason. They used to get arrested out of precaution sometimes as what happened in 1980 upon the visit of Saddam Hussein to the city of Hulla when the family was arrested out of precaution and kept in the police station for a week. Hamid was arrested many times; he was tortured gruesomely without a clear charge. This testimony was recorded in the district of Kafal on 15/12/2007."
  - Qasim Ahmad Muhammad Ali Dandal, 2008 February 9; 10.35 minutes
    "Born in 1944 in the region of Toz Khormato. An engineer officer at the rank of major. He was arrested in the early 80s without a clear charge and was transferred to a number of prisons including prison number 1. He was accused of spreading rumors, considered biased. He was sent to the Revolution Court and was sentenced to 6 years in jail. His funds were confiscated. After completing his prison sentence, he was released and was arrested once again with the charge of conspiring to overthrow the regime. He remained for several months under harsh conditions during which he was tortured, his eardrum was ruptured, but without being investigated with. He witnessed the killing of one of the prisoners with a lethal poisonous injection. This testimony was recorded in the city of Baghdad on 9/2/2008."
  - Imad Eddin Hasan Nasar Al-Musawi, 2008 May 9; 7.25 minutes
    "From the city of Al-Naseriah. He was arrested in 1994 with one of his brothers accused of joining a religious party he was tortured throughout his arrest. He saw some prisoners being tortured gruesomely in prison camps, some of which had died. He was infected in prison with some malign diseases. This testimony was recorded in the city of Nazareth on 9/5/2008."